(213) 601-9829 Los Angeles/Berkeley, California thethinkingben@berkeley.edu

Benjamin Aleman

Github: github.com/

Hello! My name is Benjamin Aleman and I'm currently interested in the research program you're conducting. While I may not have the most experience in research ventures I believe I can make it up with my experience in previous outreach endeavors and employing my rigor from them along with my developing knowledge of Python.

EDUCATION

University of California Berkeley,

Berkeley, CA

BA in Astrophysics; minor in Creative Writing; GPA 3.18/4.0

Expected Grad. 2024

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are mainly focused on computational Astrophysics. Focusing on simulating and observing any cosmological object or phenomena

SKILLS

Tools and Languages

Python, ŁTĘX, MarkDown, Google Drive

Libraries

MatPlotlib, Numpy, Scipy, Astropy, Pandas, Jupyter

Communication English

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Pvthon Decal

2021 - 2022

Worked to create a simulation of a binary star system with vast libraries and creating object oriented programs

• Collaborator: I collaborated with group to utilize object oriented programs to apply vectors and appropriate physics equations for both stars in a binary system and planets orbiting one of the said stars

RESEARCH TALKS

Python Decal Final:

Scheduled to present the research and work done to simulate a binary star system with their associated planets

OUTREACH/TEACHING

Peer Mentor/Advisor,

Berkeley, CA

SPS Berkeley

January 2021 — Present

- Co-mentor for one of the 'families' in the Society of Physics Students in Berkeley.
- Coordinate events to foster communication with new peers to create a community with each and be a mentor for anyone who need guidance.

Workshop Coordinator, AVID Site Coordinator,

Miguel Contreras Learning Complex - College 101

Los Angeles, CA January 2017 — June 2020

• I was the Head Coordinator for a weekly workshop designed. I taught multiple groups, organized materials and events, managed a group of peers while fostering cooperation

Peer Tutor/Advisor, Los Angeles, CA

Peer tutor and advisor for my school's YPI to help with college apps. and serve as an academic tutor

January 2018 — June 2020

ACTIVITIES/HOBBIES

- Writer
- Occasional Tutor